aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
100,000 Light Years of Vengeance
복수의 10만광년
Space Emperor Ark Seijin
Space Swordsman Lian
Appears
우주 황제 아크 성인
우주 검사 라이안
등장
It's a sword...
칼이다...
It's a giant's sword!
거인의 검이다!
That's some deep fog...
아아~ 안개 한번 짙게 꼈군
Captain!
선장님!
The rudder... it's not moving!
키가... 키가 움직이질 않아요!
What?
뭐야!?
Don't you know, En?
알고 있겠지, 엔?
We'll let you know what will happen if you try to make fun of us!
우리들을 바보취급 했다간 어떻게 되는지 말야
Right! We'll make you definitely understand.
그래! 똑똑히 알려주마
Heh, I guess that might be interesting.
헤에~ 알고 싶은걸
Which one is the teacher?
어느놈이 선생이냐?
You, or you?
너냐? 아니면 너냐?
Don't play jokes on us!
웃기지 마라, 이자식!
What's the problem? Just teach me already!
어떻게 된거야? 얼른 알려달라구
Or I'll teach you instead!
안그러면, 내가 가르쳐 주게 생겼는걸?
Dammit, remmeber this!
크윽, 두고봐라!
Is it end already? What fruitless guys!
벌써 끝이냐, 보람없는 녀석들이구만
Wh- who's that?!
누, 누구냐!?
Ryu!
류!
Others already flew to the pacific ocean.
다른 애들은 먼저 태평양으로 날아갔다
Pacific ocean?
태평양?
It's an investigation on the accidents on the sea recently.
최근 연속으로 일어나는 해난 사고의 조사다
What is this? This ship is totally wrecked!
뭐야... 이 배, 너덜너덜하잖아!
Moreover...
게다가, 아~아~
This is bad.
이거 심각하구만
The last record is yesterday.
최후의 기록은 어제군
Seems that they become skeletons in a single night.
아무래도 하룻밤 사이에 선원들은 백골이 된 것 같아
What the heck happened in this ship?
이 배에서 대체 무슨 일이 있었던 거지?
-Kai!
-Did you find out something?
-카이!
-뭔가 알아냈어?
Take a look at this.
이걸 보세요
I've magnified the holes on the ship,
선채에 남아있던 구멍을 확대해서 조사해 봤는데
and I have a conjecture.
한가지 추축을 하게 되었습니다
The criminal would be multiple creatures,
아마도 범인은 다수의 생물
and those would be insect, which are about 5cm long.
그것도 5Cm 정도의 곤충의 짓이라고 생각됩니다
Insect?!
곤충!?
Yes. Moreover, it's a big swarm!
게다가... 대군(大群 : 큰 무리)입니다!
Hey, just a moment!
자, 잠깐 기다려!
We're on nowhere on the sea!
여긴 바다 한가운데라구!
-What's that?
-It's going to collide!
-뭐래냐, 저건!?
-충돌한다!
What was that?
뭐야, 저건!?
I'll rescue those three. You follow that!
난 세사람을 구할게
넌 저걸 쫓아가라!
Leave it to me!
맡겨둬!
Damn, it dived!
큭, 잠수했군!
What is that guy? It transformed!
뭐야, 저녀석... 변형했잖아
Alright!
좋아!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!!
Who are you?
넌 누구냐!?
An alien from Sargasso?
사르갓소의 우주인이냐?
Just answer!
뭐라고 대답좀 해봐!
It has come to an end.
끝났다
Anything and everything.
모든것이...
Hey! What was that explosion?
이봐! 지금 그 폭팔은 뭐지!?
It's the flame of rage of 2 billions of us.
우리 20억의 분노의 불꽃이다
You bastard!
이자식!!
Don't try to be funny and answer to my question!
웃기지마! 내 질문에 대답해라!
Hmph, I have nothing to answer or something.
흥, 대답할 만한 건 아무것도 없다
No way!
그런!?
Ark Seijin?!
-아크 성인!?
Hmph, I didn't think about meeting you in the Earth, dear Ken Seijin who doesn't have a place to die.
훗, 설마 지구에서 만날 줄이야
죽을 곳 조차 없는 검성인(劍星人)이여
-You bastard!
-Ken Seijin?
-이자식!
-검성인?
Did you think that you can destroy my Ark Castle with an explosion like that?
그정도의 폭발로 나의 아크 성을 파괴할 수 있다고 생각했나?
Shut up! I came to this planet to send you to the hell!
닥쳐! 네놈을 지옥으로 떨어뜨리기 위해 나는 이 별에 온거다!
Realize the pain of 2 billion people!
똑똑히 느껴봐라! 20억 백성의 분노를!!
Stupid Ken Seijin.
어리석은 검성인이여
You bastard!
이자식!!!!!!!!
You're an eyesore.
눈에 거슬린단 말이다
Disappear!
꺼져라!!
Ark Seijin!
아크 성인!!
Hmph, I guess this will have to wait once again, Ken Seijin.
흥! 또 미루게 될 것 같군, 검성인
W- wait!
기, 기다려!
You will pay!
이자식!!!!!!
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
So you didn't come from Sargasso, right?
그럼, 넌 사르갓소에서 온게 아니라는 거군?
Do not treat a courteous Ken Seijin like those bunch.
예의바른 검성인을 그런 녀석들과 같은 취급하지 마라
Ken Seijin?
검성인?
Right. And my name is Lian.
그래, 그리고 내 이름은 라이안
Lian, judging on your look, are you an alien, or...
라이안, 너의 그 모습은 우주인인가? 아니면....
-I am a machine life-form.
-Machine life-form?
-난 기계 생명체다
-기계 생명체?
He surpassed our concept far over. In other words, he is a living robot.
우리들의 개념을 한참 초월한, 그러니까, 살아있는 로봇
Why are you going for Ark Seijin?
너는 왜 아크 성인을 노리고 있지?
-Revenge.
-Revenge?
-복수...
-복수?
Right!
그렇다!
That guy... Ark Seijin took the the lives of my friends... 2 billion lives!
녀석은... 아크 성인은 나의 동료를... 20억의 생명을 빼앗았다!
My beautiful home planet,
아름다은 나의 고향
Sword Planet.
검성(劍星)...
But...
하지만......
I saw.
나는 봤다!
Right! Ark Seijin used that devilish science to
그래! 아크 성인은 그 악마같은 과학력으로
bury Sword Planet into ice!
검성을 얼음 속으로 묻어버렸다!
After losing my friends and my home planet, I made an oath to myself to have revenge.
동료를 잃고 고향 별을 잃은 나는 복수를 맹세했다
A planet that I found 100 thousand light years away.
10만광년 끝에서 발견한 별, 지구
At there, he was there, who escaped Sargasso.
그곳에 사르갓소를 탈옥한 그 녀석이 있다
This is the chance to have a revenge!
지금이야말로 복수할 수 있는 기회다
As the sole survivor among Ken Seijins, that is my mission.
그것이 홀로 살아남은 검성인인 나의 사명이다
Alright, Lian! We Dagwons will help too!
알았어, 라이안! 우리들 다그온도 협력할게!
Let's take down Ark Seijin together!
함께 아크 성인을 해치우자!
-I reject.
-What?
-거절한다
-뭐야?
I will take down Ark Seijin by myself.
아크 성인은 내가 해치운다
The revenge is only meaningful when I take down by myself.
나 혼자서 해치워야말로 복수의 의미가 있다
To earthlings, Ark Seijin is an enemy too!
지구인에게 있어서도 아크 성인은 적이다!
Silence! It's me who'll take care of Ark Seijin.
시끄러워! 아크 성인은 내가 해치운다
Just a moment!
기다려 주세요!
Doesn't Ark Seijin have the scientific knowledge to freeze a whole planet?
아크 성인은 혹성 전체를 얼려버릴 만한 과학력을 가지고 있잖아요?
You are not a match by yourself.
너 혼자서 해치울 수 있는 상대가 아니야
I have an antimatter reactor in my body.
흥, 내 체내에는 반물질 반응로가 있다
When that guy appears again,
다음번에 녀석이 나타났을 때
I'll dash to his castle and blow myself up.
나는 녀석의 성에 돌진해서 자폭하겠다
That's stupid! What about your life?
말도안돼! 네 목숨은 어떻게 되는 거야!?
I do not value my life.
내 목숨 따윈 아깝지 않아
Lian!
라이안!
Do not interrupt my revenge!
복수를 방해하지 마라!
Lian, we're sorry, but we'll have to take care of Ark Seijin first!
라이안, 미안하지만 아크 성인은 먼저 해치워야겠다!
This is a problem! It's heading to petroleum industrial complex!
큰일이야! 석유 콤비나트로 향하고 있어!
It'll be a problem if they explode! Let's stop Ark Castle no matter what!
폭발하면 큰일이야! 아크 성을 막자!
Alright!
좋아!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!!
Shudder runs over the beautiful planet
아름다운 행성에 전율이 흐른다
Dag Fire!
다그 파이어!!
Feeling the moment the storm is coming on
폭풍이 오는 순간을 느끼며
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!!
Just like a hero inside is awakening
마음 속에서 깨어나는 영웅과 같이
Dag Turbo!
다그 터보!!
Let's go! Let's fly away! Don't look back again!
가자! 날아가자! 뒤돌아보지 마라!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!!
Dagwon... Keep on shining!! Dagwon!
다그온... 계속 빛나라! 다그온!
Dag Armor!
다그 아머!!
Get it on! It's the name of peace to love
지켜라! 사랑해야 할 평화의 이름
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!!
Dagwon... You know we are Dagwon!
다그온... 우리는 다그온!
Dag Wing!
다그 윙!!
Get it on... Nobody can take our dreams away!
우리 꿈은 그 누구도 가져갈 수 없어!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!!
Oh, please if you wanna win trust and courage
신뢰와 우정을 얻고 싶다면 꼭
Believe in believe in just believe in friendship, powerfully
믿어라 믿어라 우정을 믿어라 강력하게
Dag Shadow!
다그 섀도우!!
Do the right thing forever, don't be afraid of damage
피해에 개의치 않고 끝까지 옳은 것을 해라
Flaming Fusion!
화염합체(火炎合體)!!
Go ahead, go ahead, just go ahead for the future to dream
나아가, 나아가, 쭉 나아가라! 꿈 속의 미래를 위해!
Fire Dagwon!
파이어 다그온!!
Chaining Fusion!
중련합체(重連合體)!!
Liner Dagwon!
라이너 다그온!!
Mecha-beast Fusion!
기수합체(機獸合體)!!
Shadow Dagwon!
섀도우 다그온!!
Those idiots.
바보같은 녀석들
Are we doomed?
틀린건가?!
Lian?!
라이안!?
Ark Seijin!
아크 성인!!!!!!
You've came again?
호오, 또 왔느냐?
I won't fall for that again!
같은 수법은 통하지 않는다!!
Go to hell with me!
나와 함께 지옥으로 떨어져라!!!!!!!
Stop it, Liann!
그만둬! 라이안!!
You bastard! I told you not to meddle with my revenge!
이자식! 나의 복수를 방해하지 말라고 했을 터다!
You can die as you want!
하는건 네 마음이야!
But look!
하지만 말이다, 봐라!
We cannot make those complexes involved!
콤비나트를 말려들게 할 순 없다구!
You should be knowing that!
너도 그정돈 알고 있잖아!?
Whatever happens to this planet, I have nothing to do with.
이 별이 어떻게 되든, 나완 관계 없어!
What?
뭐야!?
Move! If you interfere, I'll take you down too!
꺼져! 방해하면 네놈도 해치우겠다!
Interesting! Do so if you're going to!
재미있군! 할 수 있다면 해봐라!
We aren't enough for this!
우리들 만으론 어쩔 수 없어!
It can't be helped. I'll try something!
할 수 없지! 내가 어떻게는 해볼게!
Liner Blizzard!
라이너 블리자드!!
How's that?
어떠냐!?
You did it! You took down Ark Seijin!
성공이야! 아크 성인을 쓰러뜨렸다구!
What?!
뭐라고!?
No way!
이럴수가?!
-Everyone!
-Now!
-얘들아!
-지금이야!
-What?!
-Now!
-뭐야?!
-지금이야!
I- I can't move!
우, 움직일 수 없어!
Lian!
라이안!
This planet is magnificent!
이 별은 대단해!
This planet has resisters worth knocking down with.
자네들 같이 해치울 가치가 있는 저항자가 있으니 말이야
How dare you, Ark Seijin!
이놈! 아크 성인!!
Your body will disassembled soon by the powerful oscillation.
초진동으로 너의 몸은 곧 산산조각으로 분해된다
Wh- what?!
아, 아니!?
I... I do not die until I kill you!
난... 난 네놈을 쓰러뜨리기 전까진 죽지 않아!!!!!!!
Lian!
라이안!!!!
Y- you...
이, 이녀석!
I- is the end?
여, 여기까지인가!?
Lian!
라이안!!
What?!
아니!?
I'm going to save you right now!
지금 구해줄 테니까 말야!
Let me go! You are going to be dismantled in this rate!
놔라! 이대론 네 몸도 분해되어 버린다!
-Silence! Just keep shut up!
-You...!
-시끄러! 좀 닥치고 있어!!
-너...!!
Fire Dagwon!
파이어 다그온!
Useless!
가만히 있어!
Now!
지, 지금이다!!
No!
아차!
You're too late!
이미 늦었어!!!!!!!
Seems that I'm worn out in a while.
오랜만에 지친 것 같군
I'll pay back the debt of today.
오늘의 빚은 갚겠다
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
kaze no naka no PRISM
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
"Do not meddle with my revenge!" Lian acted as if he was cool, and that space swordsman disappeared to somewhere.
"나의 복수를 방해하지마!"하고 폼 잡으며 혼자서 어디론가 사라진 우주 검사 라이안
But we need your help!
하지만 우리들은 너의 협력이 필요해!
What the-?! Arma Seijin's armor is too firm, and it broke my Fire Blade!
아니!? 강적 아르마 성인의 장갑이 단단해서 파이어 블레이드가 부러져 버렸어!
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! A New Comrade
다음회 용자지령 다그온
새로운 동료
Please come back, Lian!
돌아와 줘, 라이안!!
A New Comrade
새로운 동료